This video is the third and final video where we will now finish the exploit for stack level
此视频是第三个也是最后一个视频，我们现在将在其中完成堆栈级别的漏洞攻击
0 from protostar, which we have compiled on a modern system.
0来自于我们在现代系统上编译的原恒星。
In the first part we got a general overview of what has changed when the code is compiled
在第一部分中，我们大致了解了编译代码时所做的更改。
with a more modern compiler and looked more closely at the stack cookie.
使用更现代的编译器，更仔细地查看堆栈cookie。
In the second part we then ignored the cookie for now and identified a few more exploitation
在第二部分中，我们暂时忽略了cookie，并确定了更多的利用
mitigations and developed a bypass for them.
缓解措施，并为他们开发了一个旁路。
So only one thing is left.
所以只剩下一件事了。
Finally defeating the stack cookie.
最终打败了堆叠的cookie。
Like we talked about in the first video, we can bruteforce a stack cookie if the binary
就像我们在第一个视频中提到的，如果二进制文件
is a 32 bit binary.
是32位二进制。
There are around 16 million possible values for a stack cookie.
一个堆栈cookie可能有1600万个值。
That’s not that much, but 16 million executions is maybe a number where you start want to
没那么多，但1600万次处决也许是你开始想要的一个数字
optimize a bit.
优化一点。
While I’m not an expert in super fast computing, I decided I didn’t want to write a potentially
虽然我不是超级快速计算方面的专家，但我决定我不想写潜在的
slow python script, but write some C code.
python脚本很慢，但是要编写一些C代码。
But like I said I’m not an expert in what is the fastest and I actually suspect that
但就像我说的，我不是最快速度的专家，我怀疑
maybe the bottleneck here would not be a slow script, but the kernel which has to do a lot
也许这里的瓶颈不是一个缓慢的脚本，而是需要做很多工作的内核
of stuff to execute the program over and over again.
一次又一次地执行程序。
So maybe it’s unnecessary to write C code and maybe my C code is very bad too.
所以也许没必要写C代码，也许我的C代码也很糟糕。
But I just wanted to mention it that it’s not always easy to decide what is the best
但我只是想说，决定什么是最好的并不总是容易的。
approach.
方法。
Now that we said that, let’s try to approach this step by step.
既然我们已经说过了，让我们试着一步一步地接近这个问题。
First.
第一。
How do you execute a program in C. Well, there is a system call for it called exec.
你如何在C语言中执行一个程序呢，有一个系统调用称为exec。
But usually we never call syscalles ourselves directly, but use wrapper functions provided
但通常我们从不直接调用系统调用，而是使用提供的包装函数
by something like libc.
像是libc。
So libc offers a few different versions of exec, but they are ultimately all using the
所以libc提供了几个不同版本的exec，但它们最终都使用
same exec syscall underneath.
下面是相同的exec syscall。
It says here in the man page:
在手册页上写着：
“The exec() family of functions replaces the current process image with a new process
“exec() 函数系列将当前进程图像替换为新进程
image.”
形象。”
I think when you never thought about how a program is executed before, this sounds really
我想如果你以前从来没有想过程序是如何执行的，这听起来真的
weird.
奇怪的。
“Why do you replaced the current process and not just execute it?
“为什么要替换当前进程而不仅仅是执行它？
That’s so weird”.
太奇怪了”。
Well that’s just how it works, that’s the execution model of Linux.
这就是它的工作原理，这就是Linux的执行模型。
And so in our case we don’t just want to exec and thus replace our program, but we
因此，在我们的案例中，我们不只是想执行并替换我们的程序，而是
want to execute the stack0 binary as a new process over and over again.
希望反复执行stack0二进制文件作为新进程。
To spawn a new process we have to fork the process before we exec.
为了产生一个新的进程，我们必须在执行前分叉该进程。
fork() creates a new process by duplicating the calling process.
fork() 通过复制调用进程来创建新进程。
The new process is referred to as the child process.
新进程称为子进程。
The calling process is referred to as the parent process.
调用进程称为父进程。
And maybe also interesting is this down here: Difference between C library function and
还有一个有趣的地方是：C库函数和
the actual kernel.
实际内核。
Since version 2.3.3, rather than invoking the kernel's fork() system call, the glibc
因为版本2.3.3，而不是调用内核的fork() 系统调用，所以glibc
fork() wrapper [...] invokes clone(2) with flags that provide the same effect as the
fork() 包装器[…]使用提供与
traditional system call.
传统的系统调用。
So what you do to execute the process over and over is to:
因此，要反复执行这个过程，您要做的是：
First fork our current process.
首先是我们当前的进程。
now we have a child.
现在我们有了一个孩子。
An actual new separate process.
一个新的独立过程。
And you have to imagine this code is now dooplicated, we have two processes running the same code,
你必须想象这段代码现在被涂鸦了，我们有两个进程在运行相同的代码，
just one runs as the child and one runs as the parent.
只有一个作为子级运行，另一个作为父级运行。
And you can check the return value of fork which process you are.
您可以检查fork的返回值。
In the parent process you get the pid of the child.
在父进程中，您将获得子进程的PID。
In the child it’s just 0.
在孩子身上，只有0。
And then in the child process we can call exec, to replace the current process with
然后在子进程中，我们可以调用exec，将当前进程替换为
stack 0.
堆栈0。
Now in our case we want to communicate with the child.
现在在我们的例子中，我们想和孩子交流。
Meaning we want to write the exploit input to it, and read the output of it, to determine
这意味着我们要将漏洞输入写入它，并读取它的输出，以确定
if we were successful.
如果我们成功的话。
Usually you would do this by creating pipes.
通常，您可以通过创建管道来完成此操作。
pipe() creates a pipe, a unidirectional data channel that can be used for interprocess
pipe() 创建一个管道，一个可用于进程间的单向数据通道
communication.
交流。
The array pipefd is used to return two file descriptors referring to the ends of the pipe.
数组pipefd用于返回引用管道末端的两个文件描述符。
pipefd[0] refers to the read end of the pipe.
pipefd[0]是指管道的读取端。
pipefd[1] refers to the write end of the pipe.
pipefd[1]表示管道的写入端。
Data written to the write end of the pipe is buffered by the kernel until it is read
写入管道写入端的数据由内核缓冲，直到读取为止。
from the read end of the pipe.
从管道的读取端开始。
Basically the same pipe you can use on the commandline.
基本上与您可以在命令行上使用的管道相同。
You pipe stdout from one program, cat, into the stdin of another program, grep.
您将stdout从一个程序cat导入另一个程序grep的stdin。
That’s why we call this character a “pipe”.
这就是为什么我们称这个角色为“管道”。
So for basic stdin and stdout communication you would create two pipes.
所以对于基本的stdin和stdout通信，您将创建两个管道。
And then when you fork, because you clone the process, the child and the parent have
然后，当您分叉时，由于您克隆了进程，子进程和父进程
access to the same pipe.
进入同一管道。
Now obviously depending on if you are the parent or the child, you use one or the other
现在很明显，取决于你是父母还是孩子，你使用其中一个或另一个
side of it.
一边。
And in case of the child, we are actually going the replace the default stdin and stdout
对于这个孩子，我们实际上要替换默认的stdin和stdout
now with those pipes.
现在用这些管子。
By calling dup2.
打电话给dup2。
The dup2() system call performs the same task as dup(),
dup2() 系统调用执行与dup() 相同的任务，
And The dup() system call creates a copy of the file descriptor.
dup() 系统调用创建文件描述符的副本。
After a successful return, the old and new file descriptors may be used interchangeably.
成功返回后，新的和旧的文件描述符可以互换使用。
They refer to the same open file description and thus share everything.
它们引用相同的打开文件描述，因此共享所有内容。
But dup2, instead of using the lowest-numbered unused file descriptor as dup(), it uses the
但是dup2使用的不是编号最低的未使用文件描述符dup() ，而是
descriptor number specified in newfd, the second paramenter.
在第二个参数newfd中指定的描述符编号。
If the descriptor newfd was previously open, it is silently closed before being reused.
如果描述符newfd以前是打开的，那么在被重用之前，它将被静默关闭。
So dup2 closes the current stdin and stdout of the child, and plugs in the new pipe we
所以dup2关闭当前子进程的stdin和stdout，并插入新的管道
created.
创建。
And when we exec, the stack0, and replace the current process with the new one, stuff
当我们执行stack0并用新的进程替换当前进程时，
like open fildescriptors stay in tact.
像打开的窃听器一样保持机智。
So the new process will use the pipes we just connected for reading input and writing output.
所以新的过程将使用我们刚刚连接的管道来读取输入和写入输出。
And then in the parent we can simply read and write to the other end of the pipe and
然后在父系统中，我们可以简单地读写管道的另一端，
thus communicate with the child process stack0.
因此，与子进程stack0通信。
A nice thing to do is to close the ends of the pipes you are not using in either process.
要做的一件好事是关闭在这两个过程中都不使用的管道末端。
So for example we don’t need the reading side of the stdin pipe because we want to
例如，我们不需要stdin管道的读取端，因为我们希望
write, send data, to the child process.
向子进程写入、发送数据。
Ok.
好啊。
Once we have written our buffer overflow input, we can wait for the child process to finish
一旦我们编写了缓冲区溢出输入，就可以等待子进程完成。
and read the output to see if we were successful.
并读取输出以查看我们是否成功。
Now here is a first big issue.
现在是第一个大问题。
Buffering.
缓冲。
Libc will buffer output you write.
libc将缓冲您所写的输出。
So the output of the child process is buffered in the process.
因此子进程的输出在进程中得到缓冲。
And you can imagine, that if we do a buffer overflow, screw with the stack and get a segfault
你可以想象，如果我们做了一个缓冲区溢出，用堆栈拧动，得到一个segfault
this buffer is lost.
这个缓冲区丢失。
The program is just dying horribly.
这个节目真是糟透了。
But maybe you think that doesn’t make much sense, because we showed in part 2, that our
但也许你认为这没什么意义，因为我们在第2部分展示了
exploit theoretically works and we see the output on the shell.
从理论上讲，开发是可行的，我们可以看到shell上的输出。
We saw the modified variable message.
我们看到了修改后的变量消息。
SO how how does it make sense that the shell would see the output but I’m telling you
那么，shell看到输出有什么意义，但我告诉你
now, we won’t see it with the code we just have written?
现在，我们不会用刚才编写的代码看到它了吗？
Well.
好。
There is a difference to how libc buffers output depending on what kind of pipe it’s
libc如何缓冲输出取决于它的管道类型
connected to.
连接到。
And in our case we have just used regular pipes and libc will buffer the output data
在我们的例子中，我们刚刚使用了常规管道，libc将缓冲输出数据。
until the process calls flush(), or maybe until it’s filled nicely, maybe after 1024
直到进程调用flush() ，或者直到它被很好地填充，或者在1024之后
bytes or so.
字节左右。
I don’t know.
我不知道。
But we have neither, the output is super short and the child process never calls flush().
但是我们两者都没有，输出是超短的，子进程从不调用flush() 。
So what’s different on the shell.
所以外壳上有什么不同。
Well programs executed by the shell are not connected via regular pipes, but are connected
由壳牌公司执行的钻井程序不是通过常规管道连接的，而是通过常规管道连接的。
to a pseudo terminal.
到一个伪终端。
Pty.
Pty。
And when libc sees.
当libc看到的时候。
That the output is written to a pty, pseudo terminal, then it will flush() the buffer
将输出写入一个伪终端pty，然后它将刷新缓冲区() 。
upon a newline.
换行。
Because newlines are like the ultimative indication that you want to print a new line (laugh)
因为换行就像是你想要打印一行的最后指示（笑）
on the terminal output.
在终端输出上。
I think it’s like speed thing, you don’t want to flush if not necessary, but on the
我认为这就像速度一样，如果不需要的话你不想冲水，但是在
terminal you want to see outputs after a newline.
要在换行后查看输出的终端。
This means, we could also execute the stack0 program in the context of a pty, so that we
这意味着，我们也可以在一个pty的上下文中执行stack0程序，以便
fool libc into flushing on every newline.
愚弄libc在每一条新线上发泄。
And there is a convinient libc function that does that for us.
还有一个很好的libc函数，它可以为我们做到这一点。
Called forkpty()
称为forkpty() 。
The forkpty() function combines openpty (open pseudo terminal), fork(2) (which we know),
函数的作用是：结合openpty（open pseudo terminal）、fork（2）（我们知道）。
and login_tty() to create a new process operating in a pseudoterminal.
以及登录tty() 以创建一个在伪终端中运行的新进程。
The file descriptor of the master side of the pseudoterminal is returned in amaster.
在amaster中返回伪终端主端的文件描述符。
So that’s really cool.
所以这真的很酷。
We fork a child process and already get the filedescriptor so we can communicate with
我们派生一个子进程，并已经获取文件描述符，以便与
the child process.
子进程。
Then I disable a few options of the terminal, for exampel I don’t want to echo the input
然后我禁用终端的一些选项，例如，我不想回显输入。
again.
再一次。
For example if you watch my embedded hardware security CTF videos you notice that usually
例如，如果你观看我的嵌入式硬件安全CTF视频，你通常会注意到
whenever I type something on the shell to the board, I don’t see the characters I
每当我在黑板上打些东西时，我都看不到
type, that’s because I didn’t configure the terminal to echo back the characters.
类型，这是因为我没有配置终端来回送字符。
While it would have been nice there, I don’t need it here.
虽然那里会很好，但我不需要它。
And there are a few other options that could screw with what we want to do.
还有一些其他的选择可以改变我们想要做的事情。
And then we also don’t have to fiddle with pipes.
然后我们也不必摆弄管道。
So the child is just exec now.
所以这个孩子现在只是行政人员。
In the parent we define our bufferoverflow input, that’s basically the one we developed
在父级中，我们定义了缓冲溢出输入，这基本上就是我们开发的输入
last video, and then also add some random() function to get three random bytes for the
最后一个视频，然后添加一些random() 函数以获取
cookie.
饼干。
And place those into the buffer overflow string.
并将它们放入缓冲区溢出字符串中。
A simple ugly loop to avoid newlines, because that would indicate the end of our input,
一个简单的丑陋循环来避免换行，因为这将指示输入的结束，
and we dont’ want that.
我们不想那样。
Then we write the bufferoverflow string to the master filedesriptor of our pseudo terminal
然后我们将bufferoverflow字符串写入伪终端的主文件描述器
and stack0 will read it and will get exploited.
Stack0会阅读它并得到利用。
Then I create a short loop to check the status of the child, but I don’t want to block
然后我创建一个简短的循环来检查孩子的状态，但我不想阻止
and wait for it, because the child could horribly die or not die because of the buffer overflow,
等等，因为缓冲区溢出，孩子可能会死得很惨，也可能不会死，
so I just check the status a few times in a loop and if the child is dead, we continue,
所以我只是在一个循环中检查几次状态，如果孩子死了，我们继续，
If we waited already a few times we decide to kill the child process,
如果我们已经等了几次，我们决定终止儿童进程，
And otherwise we sleep a bit.
否则我们会睡一会儿。
Usually it shouldn’t loop much, as the child program is very short, but it’s a safety-net.
通常它不应该循环太多，因为儿童程序非常短，但它是一个安全网。
BTW. program ids, pids, are prone to race conditions in linux.
顺便说一句，程序ID，PIDS，在Linux中很容易出现竞争条件。
You see we don’t have some kind of handle direclty pointing to the child process, we
你看，我们没有直接指向子进程的句柄，我们
only have the number.
只有号码。
And numbers can be reused.
数字可以重复使用。
So theoretically our child could have died, another process like a webserver could have
所以从理论上讲，我们的孩子可能已经死了，另一个像网络服务器这样的进程可能已经死了。
been executed and assigned our old pid, and then we kill it here.
被执行并分配了我们的旧PID，然后我们在这里杀死它。
And there is no better way, linux is just really ugly some times.
没有更好的方法，Linux有时真的很难看。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
One other thing I want to add now is a signal handler, which will be notified if the child
我现在要添加的另一件事是信号处理程序，如果孩子
dies or so.
模具等。
We could just read the output after the wait, but we don’t know why and how the child
我们可以在等待之后读取输出，但我们不知道为什么以及如何
might die and so forth, and I also found it to be a third slower if I do that.
可能会死等等，我也发现如果我这样做的话会慢三分之一。
So used the signal handler instead.
因此使用了信号处理程序。
This handler function is called to notify us if anything happens to the child.
调用这个处理程序函数来通知我们如果孩子发生了什么事情。
So when it receives a SIGCHLD.
所以当它收到信号时。
And in the handler function we then read from the terminal the output of stack0.
然后在handler函数中，我们从终端读取stack0的输出。
First we read the “Try again?”
首先我们读到“再试一次？“
message.
消息。
And then potentially read the stack smashing detected error, OR maybe the successful modified
然后可能读取堆栈粉碎检测到的错误，或者成功修改
variable message.
变量消息。
Or maybe nothing.
或者什么都没有。
Then I do an ugly check of the second output to see the success message.
然后我对第二个输出进行丑陋的检查，以查看成功消息。
If that’s the case we print it and we are done.
如果是这样的话，我们就打印出来，然后就完成了。
So now it’s basically ready.
现在基本上准备好了。
I add some more debug output to see whats going on, add an argument to supply a seed.
我添加了更多的调试输出来查看发生了什么，添加了一个参数来提供种子。
and then we can compile it.
然后我们可以编译它。
Because we want to use forkpty, we have to also link the utils library.
因为我们要使用forkpty，所以还必须链接utils库。
Here you can see how many executions we get per second per process.
在这里，您可以看到每个进程每秒执行多少次。
This machine has only one CPU, so this will take a while, let’s come back later.
这台机器只有一个CPU，所以这需要一段时间，我们稍后再来。
Let’s see.
让我们看看。
Mhhm… nothing happened yet.
嗯……还没发生什么事。
Maybe let’s rent a bigger server for a few hours with more CPU cores.
也许让我们租一个更大的服务器，用更多的CPU内核，用几个小时。
Mmh maybe this one.
嗯，也许是这个。
Now to run it I do some ghetto parallelisation.
现在，为了运行它，我做了一些犹太人区的平行化。
But oh what.
但是，哦，什么？
Only 9 executions per second, what kind of crap is that?
每秒只有9次处决，那是什么垃圾？
If you look at the processes you can see something called apport.
如果您查看这些流程，您可以看到称为apport的内容。
Apport is a system which: intercepts crashes right when they happen
Apport是一个系统，它可以在发生崩溃时截获崩溃。
the first time, gathers potentially useful information about
第一次，收集有关
the crash and the OS environment,
崩溃和操作系统环境，
Ah, so because we constantly crash a process this thing is gatehring information and slowing
啊，所以，因为我们不断地破坏一个过程，这件事就是传递信息和减慢速度。
everything down.
一切都结束了。
Let’s disable this service.
让我们禁用此服务。
And then let’s wait for a bit.
然后我们再等一会儿。
AWWW YEAH!
是啊！
See, one process output the modified variable message.
请参见，一个进程输出修改后的变量消息。
How amazing is that.
真是太神奇了。
I admit not the most reliable exploit, but it worked.
我承认这不是最可靠的利用，但它起作用了。
I’m happy.
我很高兴。
If you have a better exploit strategy for this here, please share it with us.
如果您在这里有更好的开发策略，请与我们分享。
I’m really curious what other techniques could be used to exploit this program in a
我真的很好奇还有什么技术可以用来利用这个程序
more reliable way.
更可靠的方法。
Thanks guys, see you next time.
谢谢各位，下次见。